RICHARD STOKES

Software Engineer | Data Engineer | UX/UI Designer

714.875.1271 | rickydottech@gmail.com | TX. CA. NY, United States

SUMMARY: I am a premier software engineer with 13 years of experience in creating remarkable software applications, specializing in languages like Python, C++, PHP, and JavaScript. Armed with these engineering skills, I have led notable engineering teams, founded successful startups, and significantly boosted corporate revenues. Additionally, I've had the privilege of speaking at colleges and mentoring minority students in technology. With my expertise, you can expect enhancements in your product's appeal, usability, integrity, and functionality. Here's a glimpse of my expertise:

S O F T W A R E									
	CODE >		CMS		FRAMEWORKS / LIBRARIES				
0 0 0	HTML, CSS, SCSS JavaScript, TypeScript PHP C++, Swift Python Swift Go	14 yrs. 10 yrs. 10 yrs. 8 yrs. 3 yrs. 3 yrs. 1 yr.	WordPressMagentoJoomla!ShopifyDrupal	11 yrs. 6 yrs. 3 yrs. 3 yrs. 3 yrs.	JavaScript: [React.js, Angular.js, Vue.js, Ionic, Electron, jQuery, Backbone.js, Meteor.js] Python: [PyQt, Flask, Django, Numpy, PyTorch] PHP: [Zend, CakePHP, Laravel, Symfony] C++: [ifStream, TensorFlow, Tonic, SeqAn]				

NETWORK CLOUD DATA IoT											
UTILITY 💗		CLOUD 👁		DATABASE 🚳		AI/ML/LLM					
 Terraform Kubernetes / Docker Prometheus GitHub / Bit (Pro) Jira / Notion / Clickup Trello / Sonoma Mixpanel /FullStory 	5 yrs. 5 yrs. 2 yrs. 12 yrs. 4 yrs. 2 yrs. 6 yrs.	° Google Cloud (GCP) ° AWS EC2 [Kafka, ELB, s3, Lambda ° Microsoft Azure ° SiteGround ° Snowflake ° Cloudflare	9 yrs. 8 yrs. 1, CF, etc] 5 yrs. 3 yrs. 1 yr. 10 yrs.	 MongoDB MySQL / SQL FireBase PostgreSQL DynamoDB InfluxDB ClickHouse 	3 yrs. 12 yrs. 5 yrs. 4 yrs. 2 yrs. 2 yrs. 2 yrs.	0 0 0	PaLm LLAMA DALL-E Falcon Gemini TensorFlow Framer.ai				

CAREER EXPERIENCE

- FilmOn.TV (Jan. 2014 July 2014) Software Engineer: Developed and managed team built web framework Description: PHP, JavaScript, C++ (ifstream) / Apache Server, LevelDB & mongoDB.
- At&t (Oct. 2013 May 2014) Network Technician: Commercial & Residential IT. Description: Setup WAN/LAN, Subnetworks, Switches, Firewalls and ran 5- point network test, cat5e & fiber installs.
- DS Services (May 2014 July 2015) Oracle Data Analyst: Audited incoming and outing inventory. Description: Data entry, Oracle Database Management, Inventory Auditing, Database integration.
- ECR World / IQA (July 2015 May 2016) e-Commerce Manager *Contract. Description: WordPress / Magento Developer, eBay API integration, IT support & electronics repair technician.
- Shooger (August 2016 March 2017) Full Stack Developer / Mobile App Developer Description: Full Stack Developer: WordPress front & backend, xCode & Android Studio for Shooger mobile app.
- BrandRep (Jan. 2017 June 2017) Full Stack Developer / Optimization Specialist Description: Full Stack Developer: WordPress front & backend, xCode & Android Studio for Shooger mobile app
- Prima Marketing (July 2017 Feb. 2018) Software Engineer & IT. Description: Joomla, Squarespace & WordPress front & backend developer. PHP, JavaScript & cartSpan.
- NBD Corporation (March 2018 July 2019) Full Stack Engineer, Data Analyst & Network Specialist. Description: WordPress & Angular web app front and backend developer, marketing campaign management, KPI's, AWS & Google Cloud administrator, API integration, e-Commerce management, network installation, computer setup.
- Visual Embassy (January 2016 2020) Founder, Lead Engineer Description: We built over 150+ e-commerce applications for clients using Upwork, Fiver and e-lance.
- Code & Silver (November 2019 Current) Project Manager, Full Stack Developer, IT Description: Software project manager & Lead network technician responsible for the construct of websites, web frameworks, cloud infrastructure, UI / UX design and client consultations.
- Smith & Noble (March 2020 April 2023) Senior Software Engineer Description: Lead Engineer responsible for Magento backend, React UX/UI, data structure, aggregation and throughput, increasing web performance and optimization, unit metrics, user-behavior, developing API's, etc.
- Blacksteel Capital (March 2022 April 2023) Co-founder & CTO Description: Lead Python Engineer, Data Structure and Algorithmic Design Patterns, Blockchain integration, etc.
- Buyable (April 2023 April 2024) Co-founder & Chief Product Officer **Description**: Go-to-Market specialist, Product market fit strategist, backend / frontend software engineer, social marketing strategic planning, digital consumer facing technical facilitator, constructed LLM Models, built, tested and automated AI/ML frameworks, created embed technology, API endpoint management.

FORMAL EDUCATION

- **Tennessee State University**
- Computer Science
- · (2009-2012)
- Vanderbilt University
 - IT Research and Development Team. (2010 - 2011)
- Techstars NYC Alumni Business accelerator program (March 2023 - August 2023).

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Design Tools

- Photoshop [8 yrs.]
- Illustrator [5 yrs.]
- Adobe AEM
- Adobe XD

Network | IT

- * IP Mapping / NAT
- * Active Directory
- * LAN / WAN mapping
- Port Forwarding
- * Router Configuration * Firewall Configuration
- * Sub Networking
- Reverse Proxy Setup
- * MS SharePoint
- * TAP Net Analyzer

* DMZ Zone

- * DNS WKGRP NAS Setup
- * Switch Configuration
- * Network Mounting
- * DNS Configuration

linkedin.com/in/stokes-richard/